# JAMES E. (JED) DAVIS

₫ 8700 Brodie Lane #1414 ■ Austin, Texas 78744 🕿 469.358.5333 🖂 jed.davis.email@gmail.com

# QUALIFICATIONS PROFILE

A highly analytical, innovative, and well-organized professional with proven expert in interpersonal communication and exceptional at dealing with clients and customers. Equipped with broad experience in the coordination and implementation of on-air and online content, as well as advertising for multiple radio station websites.

## **Competitive Advantage**

- Demonstrates strong presentation, negotiation, and communication skills with the ability to build top-producing relationships with customers and business partners worldwide.
- Valued team player with enviable capacity to formulate and execute strategies and initiatives to support corporate mission.
- Exceptional in championing new growth opportunities through market analysis, product development expertise, and keen business instincts.

# RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

# iHeartMedia - Austin

#### **Integrated Brand Manager**

August 2013 - Present

- Partnered with station marketing managers, on-air talent, and the entire market team in to deliver the best on-air and digital consumer experience. Including copy writing for on-air/streaming, Banner Ads and Targeted Display.
- Worked in conjunction with the digital department to propose, close, and implement station specific advertising and promotional contracts with local, state, and national clients.
- Ensured on-air promotions, contests, events, and activities were synced with web components.
- Coordinated sales and digital activations for key community and station events such as, but not limited to: SXSW, Country Music Live Series, and Texas Tailgate Zone.

#### Cox Media Group - Austin

# **Multimedia Advertising Consultant**

2012 - 2013

- Sold advertising and event marketing to specific territory in East Austin.
- Traveled with in my territory to individual businesses presenting print, direct mail and print/deliver opportunities.
- Presented Social Media Marketing, SEO/SEM and Targeted Display for Web.
- Made a minimum of 5 face to face contacts per day, and a minimum of 10 proposals and price quotes per week.
- Kept daily log of contact, presentations and renewals in Salesforce.

## DealerTrack Inc - Dallas

Sales Manager 2011 - 2012

- Sold a java based managed chat service to car dealership in central United States.
- Demonstrate with online presentation through gotomeeting.com with multimedia visual proposals and PowerPoint.
- Made a minimum of 30 contacts per day, and a minimum of 10 proposals a week.
- Assist web development team with implementation of software to dealer website.
- Keep daily log of contact, presentation and renewals in Saleforce.

## Viamedia TV - Grapevine

#### Account Executive

2011 - 2011

- Identify demographic advertising needs for advertising on the Verizon FiOS Cable Network.
- Create and propose advertising recommendations that best suit customer needs through multimedia visual proposals and PowerPoint.
- Prepare accurate advertising contracts on behalf of the Viamedia TV.
- Coordinate and assist with production plans; assist in coordination of external production.
- Assist with special projects, which include on-site promotions at city events and festivals.

# Dallas Observer - Dallas

Account Executive 2009 - 2011

- Managed an average of 200 active accounts to grow revenue in the Dallas market in an alternative, weekly print/online sales
  environment.
- Grew online revenue for <a href="www.dallasobserver.com">www.dallasobserver.com</a> and VVM partner websites including <a href="www.urbanspoon.com">www.urbanspoon.com</a>
   <la>www.urbanspoon.com</a>
   <la>www.urbanspoon.com</a>
   <la>www.urbanspoon.com</a>
- Co-developed large sponsorship marketing campaigns and events with the marketing department. 2010 Dallas Observer Music Awards Showcase took place in Deep Ellum, TX.

# JAMES E. (JED) DAVIS

€ 8700 Brodie Lane #1414 ■ Austin, Texas 78744 🕿 469.358.5333 🖂 jed.davis.email@gmail.com

#### Cumulus Radio - Dallas

Account Executive 2008 - 2009

- Grow revenue share for KDBN 93.3 The Bone in the Dallas/Ft.Worth metroplex in a classic rock radio station environment.
- Worked closely with national advertising agencies that included OMD, Carat & SpotPlus to develop targeted campaigns to drive traffic for their specific clients.
- Prospect new business using all media outlets for on-air, non-traditional and streaming advertising. Maintained three daily face-toface appointment schedules for developing new business. Assist with special projects, which include on-site promotions at city events and festivals.

#### **BMG Music Publishing** - Carrollton

Account Executive 2006 - 2008

- Grow market share for FirstCom Music in radio/TV outlets in the southeastern United States utilizing inside sales. Selling production music, jingle packages and hardware for creative services departments.
- Maintain current production music account list, over 400 radio and television stations, by up-selling new production music, hard drives and web access.
- Develop new business by cold calling and e-marketing. Made a minimum of 80 new business cold calls a day.
- Understand client's current production music needs, and be able to develop and qualify needs into a customized solution.
- Strong phone selling skills, including expertise in qualifying, negotiating and closing.

## CBS Radio - Dallas

Account Executive 2003 - 2006

- Grow market share for KLLI with the men 25 54 demographic by developing new business and increasing current billing accounts by 5% or more.
- Maintain current account list of over 50 billing accounts, marketing and collections. Clients varied in type, from Blue Bell Ice Cream to 4 Wheel Parts.
- Prospect new business using all media outlets. Internet, newspaper, billboards, magazines.
- Understand ROI of radio advertising, and be able to develop and defend the value that contributes to ROI and convey the values to prospects and existing accounts.
- Strong phone selling skills, including expertise in qualifying, negotiating and closing.

# Clear Channel Radio - Dallas

Account Executive 2001 - 2003

- Learn the business of radio advertising and how to grow market share for KEGL with the men 18 34 demographic.
- Build account list from new business and maintain a list of accounts provided sporadically by sales manager, marketing and collections.
- Prospect new business using all media outlets (i.e. billboards, magazine, internet and competition comparison).
- Strong phone selling skills, including expertise in qualifying, negotiating and closing.
- Understand ROI of radio advertising, and be able to develop and defend the value that contributes to ROI and convey the values to prospects and existing accounts.

# **EDUCATION**

Austin Coding Academy, Austin, TX

**Full Stack Web Development** 

2015-2016

## TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint) | Adobe Photoshop | Salesforce | HTML 5 | CSS | Javascript | php | Laravel | SQLite | Search Engine Optimization | Dreamweaver | Viero | Fusion